Good morning or afternoon rather.
Yeah, I get it.
I get it. How are you doing?
Oh, I'm okay. Well, I mean, that's how I'm doing.
Yeah. It's so funny. I was joking with, uh, um,
I'm not sure if you, if every, has everything been good
with your, with your winter?
Like you've had no challenges or Hopefully,
Um, I mean, it's, this is, I,
I I believe this is like the coldest
snap we've ever experienced.
Yeah. Um, So, you know, there's that like, it,
it's not uncommon to experience minus 20, uh,
but it is uncommon to have it last forever.
Yeah. Yeah. I joked with, uh, I had a call with, with pol
and I was like, you know, as a Floridian,
like I've always had this rule of like, I,
I can't bring myself to turn the heat on.
Like, I can't, like, it's like, it, it's 35, it's like,
it's cold here, it's low thirties, like, that's cold.
But I'm like, yeah, no, I, I'm not until my wife, I'm like,
look, just figure it out.
Throw a sweatsuit on. We're, we're not turning the heat on.
And this weekend I, I finally caved because I was working
and I couldn't feel my hands, literally.
I'm like, and I looked and my thermostat was like, almost,
it was like 61 degrees in the house.
Wow. And I was, I can't,
you know, everyone has their limits.
So you Went on as of yesterday
and it's, you know, it's, uh, something,
How long is it? How long
are you expected to have this cold snap?
I don't know. I mean, you know, we're not,
we're not in anything dangerous.
My brother's like two hours from me
and he, um, he had it where it's like, it was about 25.
And he goes, you know, that's where it gets interesting.
He goes, 'cause this could potentially freeze our pipes,
or, you know, I was like, yeah,
I've never dealt with that in my life.
I, I certainly have known people in Texas
where their infrastructure starts.
There starts to be a lot of complications.
Like, let's say their water freezes and their pipes
and stuff, or their power goes out for weeks
and it's incredibly cold.
That's a tough challenge.
Um, but no, I mean, it, nothing happened.
I called him and he said
that they didn't have any issues and, and stuff like that.
So thankful. And yeah, I don't know how long it will last.
I mean, it's typically
whenever, whatever's going on in the country.
So when people are like, oh my gosh,
it's gonna be like when you're like, it's gonna be
insanely cold, that's when my cold front for me is as well.
Yeah. So same time as everything else. It seems like
It feels though, like it's sort of, it fell early January
and there it stayed.
So like, again, like we, there's a lot of,
um, ebbs and flows.
So not uncommon from minus 20,
but you know, you get three, four days of minus 20,
and then it's sort of more like minus three, minus one.
Yep. And, uh, nope. Nope.
What's been like, and with the windchill, it's been
approaching minus 50 on some days,
so it's, it's quite dang. Yeah.
And so are you in, um, you have three kids, right?
I sure do. Yeah.
So are you, I assume that like, you're just like, there's no
outside in that, right? You're just sort of
No, there really isn't. So,
you know, everybody's kinda gets,
I the middle kid who's, uh, 11
will go out and, uh,
and really, yeah, they'll hang out with friends
or they're in and out of neighborhood houses and stuff.
So that's, that's nice for them.
'cause they're pretty social, but
the other two are like, Nope.
It's like, don't freeze. Yeah.
Geez. Well, and we thought, we thought that they got some,
um, frost nip, like, not frostbite,
but you know, the ears were red and numb
and tingling, um, for a couple days, so mm-hmm.
You know, it happens and it, yeah. You
Gotta, you gotta put your mom hat on real quick.
Uh, I assume, geez.
Well, how are you feeling about the, um, the cohort today?
I know you had some questions,
which made total sense. Um, yeah,
I was just listening through the run of show
and I was well, and,
and comparing them to what happened in the, like, the video.
Uh, and just noticed a couple of things.
So I wasn't sure if we should come up with like,
the various examples to talk through or whether, you
Know. Yeah. I'll just tell you
too. 'cause like, when we met,
like the week of, like I was telling you, Dale
and I would meet like once a week
for whatever the next stuff is.
And so the plan was that I had, I have been in a role
as an account manager, which is client success,
and he goes, Hey, because you've, um, you know, done this,
I'm gonna, I'm just throw it to you for like five minutes
and then you can give like a real example.
And so I, I think what I wrote was like a framework of like,
hey, what most people do.
And it was just for me to like, speak it in that way.
So it, it's a little like consumed a little bit better,
but I don't think I put anything there.
Um, I was just going to say, I, I was an account manager
for a very large coaching company
that did about 50 million a year,
and we created like pinpoints, um, uh,
throughout our client success journey.
And I was gonna share that.
And then also, like, and,
and one big, I think like whatever you saw,
and I haven't looked at it in a while,
but it was, it was more like the biggest issues that I see
with companies when they're looking at client success.
And I put like, do.dot, like I was just gonna kinda
have a cadence for how I communicated it,
but don't worry, like, as you saw it, never, um,
we never got to that point.
I just think with timing, it just
Never happened. Well, and I, and
I think that given
that you are delivering the, like, meat of the session,
that can be woven into the sort
of ascension points, um, yeah. As well, right?
Yeah. I, I won't, like, I don't plan on it again,
like I'm going over everything.
Um, you know, we'll, we'll keep it high level, I think
for you, um, in the, in the intro, just try to, um,
I had a couple suggestions.
So like, obviously you're gonna do the, the normal stuff,
like the welcome everybody.
Mm-hmm. Um, you know, here's where we're in the timeline.
This is where you should be up to this point, the poll.
Um, and then I,
I think there's a breakout session this one too, right?
Yeah. Okay. So I was gonna say you could,
you could make the breakout session a bit longer. Yeah,
I have Minutes.
Yeah, I was just gonna say, like,
you could do maybe like 14 minutes
or, you know, technically 15.
'cause it, it has like that 60 ki um,
and the only thing I was gonna tell you, just quickly
update the slide if you do that, just
because it, I think it always says like,
this breakout will be 10 minutes,
but I think that that might be good.
And, um, for what it says on the doc, what I, 'cause
'cause I'll just leave that to you to set it up,
but, um, what I would say, whatever it says, like, Hey,
I forgot what it says, but like, hey, just go
through whatever your best is and then like your worst.
Mm-hmm. And then give them an example so you could say, Hey,
I'm Midori, um, you know, I'm at this company,
I help agency owners get result.
Um, right now I'm, I'm really, really good in fulfillment,
um, not great at asking
for referrals or something like that.
Yeah. And so I have that, I have that input,
or what I have here is breakout.
Um, yeah.
Just sort of like, we're great at delivering results,
but we can't seem to get
that review from Perfect, for example.
And I was just gonna tell you
because they'll have the time.
I was just gonna tell you, I think it would help if you
added like a tag to it.
That would be something like, and once you all go around
and you understand what, what you do
and what you're great at in your delivery to success,
I think what would be helpful is to have an open discussion.
For example, you can learn a lot from somebody
who might say, I'm really great at referrals.
Mm-hmm. And then after you go around,
have an open discussion and,
and I think think it will be helpful to,
to learn from each other.
And if you give that, I think it'll fill the,
the time really, um, really well.
Okay. Um, so yeah, that was the only suggestion.
I mean, it's a lot, it's a lot to go over,
but also it tends to go fairly quickly.
Yeah. Um, So if you just elongated that, I will,
you know, I'll always do my best in
the delivery of this stuff.
I mean, I, I know what it is, I'm just sort
of saying it my way, but, um, you know, sometimes it's,
it tends to just, I, I tend to be done with it
because I have not been looking at it like the run of show.
And perhaps I should, but I don't, like,
I don't look at this and be like, this is 30 minutes.
I just kind of like, look at the slides
and then listen to how Dale did it.
And I just kind of like, repeat that in my own way.
Um, so this will probably help us in that regard.
Um, I'll also end up sharing the Notion template.
Okay. Um, because we actually don't even use, we did,
the cool thing is I'll be able to reference it
because we used to use Notion to store our SOPs,
which it's gonna be a part of this, um, session as like how
to organize and store your SOPs for your company, like
outside of Clogged, like what we're doing here.
Um, and so we're, we're touching on that,
and I, I'm gonna share my screen
and I'll, I'll show people like, Hey, we actually used
to use Notion as a company, so you can kind of have an idea
of what that looks like, and I'll show it for this business,
and then I'll, I'll end up going to delivery to Success,
which is, is what today's session is on.
And that way they can just have a visual with that.
Um, while also knowing that like,
we're gonna put these people in stage three at some point.
Um, I actually thought that Hayden was gonna tell me to do
that now because earlier,
or excuse me, late, late last week, he was talking
to me about, um, how people are, um,
how we, we, we might have like an addition to this session,
uh, to introduce stage three.
And he actually had like a prompt that I saw,
and it was like a, you know, like a tutorial on how to join
and how to upload your SOPs.
So that exists. But, um, he hasn't said that this is, uh,
in it, um, or he might put it in the curriculum,
but not really part of the training, uh,
of the actual session.
So I guess we'll, we'll kind of see how that, that,
Yeah. Those were sort of my
big questions when
I was going through the run of show.
And when I was, uh, watching the video,
it felt a little bit like, even by the last cohort, you were
all moving away from Notion in terms
of like focusing more on enterprise businesses
and it doesn't really, it's not a suitable application.
Yep. And I'll, I'll certainly take, uh,
I'll certainly mention that the same way Dale done.
I'll say, I'm like, look, notion is great.
It's a great piece of software. We used it internally.
We're a team of about 10 people mm-hmm. For clarity.
Like we're a small business.
Um, and so Notion,
and a lot of people are familiar with Notion
because of, uh, Tia, like Tiago uses Notion in his company,
which, which a lot of these people kind of came from either.
Either they came from Tiago directly
or they found the interviews
with Hayden and Tiago on YouTube.
So one of those buckets.
So a lot of people are familiar with Notion. Mm-hmm.
And it's, you know, it's just one of those things.
Um, so, um, yeah, with that, I'll just go
through everything, um, you know,
through the main run of show.
Let me take a look at this here.
So, I mean, the only, I guess the only question I had is,
you know, I've, uh, I'll go over
sort of all of the next steps.
So like the, the six pieces of work that we're getting to,
uh, between now and Friday,
and that's now and Friday, right?
Uh, like you have a, the longer chunk of time,
because Wednesday is office hours
where we can really pick up Correct.
From even Session one and sort of dive deep into it. Um,
And remember this session's a little bit different.
'cause again, we're just sort
of doing what we did last time.
And it was interesting for me to watch it again.
But, so I actually show, I actually share the screen and,
and like go over stuff.
I didn't do the assessment in Claw this time.
Um, however, like,
I'm just gonna go over the prompts in high level detail,
like, okay, this is the five s, you're gonna add it
to your master prompt, and I'm gonna go over that.
And then we will, we'll go through all of the stuff.
We'll do a q and a,
and then when we feel good, I will share the screen again
for like the final slides for you to kind of take us home.
Okay. And so I'm not gonna share screen at that time.
What I'll do is just sort of say, uh, you know,
as we've already seen, these are the prompts for this week.
These are the six exercises.
So yeah. As Josh showed you, uh, I'm just gonna,
just gonna clarify your next steps following this session.
Josh went over things and in high detail earlier,
but this is for everyone to see.
So after it add your five Rs to the master prompts,
it's basically gonna go over the slide itself.
And then we also have our first office hours.
I, I think it's Wednesday. Wednesday,
Yeah. Yeah.
So just going over those last two, like next steps,
which is what you, you're gonna go over quickly,
what I go over more in detail.
Mm-hmm. And then, and also, um, our next sessions,
we have an office hours is if you guys are going
through this and you want to join and, and unpack that
and have open discussions, this is really, um,
for whatever you're, you're needing.
Mm-hmm. As well as we have our next session on, uh,
whatever it is, next on Friday.
I think it's, uh, uh, either marketing
or, I'm not sure. I think
It's market Yeah. Marketing and brand.
Marketing and brand, right. Yeah. So, yeah.
So I'm doing, so this week, um, I got the sessions
and then, um, I know, I think Hayden's doing
office hours the following Monday session.
'cause I think it's like profitability stuff.
He just knows more about that stuff. Okay. Ooh.
So we'll wait a little bit here.
We got, I see like three people.
Okay, now we got four mike's coming through.
Um, sometimes I like to, uh, Hayden
and I do this, like, we'll, we'll,
we'll start it at like one
after, just if more people show up or something.
But you have of course,
autonomy to, to do whatever you want.
I'm gonna run to the bathroom very
quickly and we'll be good to go.
Okay.
All right. Yeah, let's get it.
Okay. I'm gonna start letting people in. Is that okay?
Yep.
Hi, Nancy. Mike, Jonathan.
Tim, Benny. Good to see everybody.
Hi guys. Good to see you. Hello.
All right.
Hello. Hello.
Welcome to the start of week two. Hello.
Nice to see everyone here.
Uh, this is the fourth session for Empower Labs Cohort four.
Uh, great to see everyone again, my name is Midori
and I'm co-facilitating
with Josh who's gonna lead us through today's session.
Uh, today we're going
to be focusing on expansion capability.
In other words, today we're gonna be developing systems
that facilitate easy and seamless growth.
Uh, but before we dive in, uh, let's take a few moments
to look at what we've covered so far
and where we are in the timeline.
Again, as I said, we're in session four, uh,
and that's four of 13th.
Last week was our foundation's week,
and we had three sessions together.
Going forward, we're only going to be meeting twice a week
for our live sessions on generally on Mondays and Fridays.
And on Wednesdays, we're gonna be hosting some,
uh, office hours.
So, so far, uh, we've established a strong foundation
by covering how to utilize Claude
for your business processes.
You've made progress in developing your core processes, uh,
and our focus today shifts in transforming your
customer base into significant growth
engines for your business.
Uh, I'm about to launch a check-in poll just to gauge, uh,
how we are all, uh, doing, uh,
it's just a one question.
And the question is, uh, on whether
or not you've managed to complete, partially complete
or not yet start, um, uh,
the exercises from session three.
So here we go, launching the poll.
Now, if you don't mind taking a
moment to answer that, that would be really helpful to sort
of get a sense of, uh, of where we're at
and how folks are doing as we head into this new week.
Alright. It looks like everyone's voted.
Do you wanna share that poll?
Here we go. Sharing the results.
So it looks like, uh, most of you are partially completed.
Uh, 20% have completed it. Congratulations to you.
And the great news is everyone has.
So that's, that's really good.
Uh, so thanks for taking the time, uh, to answer that.
Uh, and if you, if you could, we are looking
for some I insights.
Uh, if you're willing to share, uh, any insights into
what it was like assessing your documentation in this first
core process, um, please feel free to ra uh, share
by raising your hand and unmuting yourself.
Uh, otherwise you can also type some, uh,
thoughts into the chat directly,
whatever feels most accessible to you.
But what were your key takeaways?
That's what we're looking for today.
Um, any surprises, any insights, uh,
from this documentation process?
Did anything Claude generate, uh, give you a new perspective
or highlight an immediate need
for change in your current methods?
Um, was there a crucial step that, uh,
Claude identified that you'd overlooked?
Uh, we'd appreciate hearing, uh,
your initial thoughts on this.
I'm just gonna look at the chat,
see if there's anything there.
Don't be shy guys. You can unmute yourselves as well.
Yeah. So, hi, this is Don,
who hasn't figured out how to raise his hand yet.
Anyway. Um, shall I go on, please?
Yeah, go ahead, Don.
Share your experience. That'd be helpful.
Okay. Okay. Midori, uh,
and Josh, uh, so I, um,
am delighted with the, uh, output from Claude
because of its power, uh, to communicate
with the others that I'm dealing with.
Mm-hmm. And so that is, uh,
that's hugely valuable.
It, it creates a opening for me to, uh, you know,
increase my, um, influence
and cause the company to, uh, excel faster.
And so just the conversation that we're going to have
around those documents that were created is gonna be, uh,
worth the price of admission, I expect.
Excellent. Well, thank you for sharing.
We probably have time for one more.
Maybe, uh, before we kinda get into today's session,
I also see a few, uh, comments in the chat here.
Yeah. Go ahead and read. Yeah.
So, uh, Jo says, we have a lot of work in front of us.
I can relate to that. Uh, uh, FM buyer says,
second time doing this with a different company.
And, and I remain impressed with the level of detail
that Claude identifies I have, uh,
to course correct a little,
but I love the attention to detail.
It's bringing up steps that are there, uh,
that I had overlooked or taken for granted.
Um, I think we hear that quite frequently.
Um, also reading here, I realized
that I definitely need internal sessions
to bring the knowledge of my partners into this.
Uh, didn't think it, it would go so deep. Yeah.
Uh, and Christina says, uh, the level
of detail is mind blowing,
so many dark corners I haven't looked into yet.
Mm-hmm. Uh, yep.
Benny too high on owner involvement for sure.
But that's, remember for you and,
and anybody else, that's exactly why you're doing this.
Remember that final tag that we'll consistently see, AI has
a tendency to sort of, you know, make very grand,
almost enterprise level plans.
And that sort of last prompt of like, Hey,
is this appropriate for a company
of my size is gonna continuously be really important for you
and, and kind of everybody else.
And then, um, Mike realized we need to define by role, not
by person, since many individuals have multiple roles.
So cutting down gods from 15 to eight,
all really good insights,
and hopefully that's helpful as, as multiple of
of you share, uh, just to kind of see
what everyone else is going through.
Yeah. So thank you so much for your thoughts,
your tensions, your insights.
Uh, it's very helpful, um, to hear what's coming up.
Uh, we have such a range of expertise in this room.
We have a range of experience with AI enablement, uh,
and a range of, um, business types and sizes as well.
Uh, but that said, it's always helpful
to hear from each other.
I think common themes pop up no matter where you're,
uh, starting from.
Uh, and so now I'm just gonna overview of what we're going
to be doing in today's sessions.
Uh, there's three main points
that we're going to be diving into.
The first is where Josh is gonna take us through the five Rs
of customer, uh, excellence.
This is a framework that shows us how
to take a satisfied customer, uh,
and turn it into your business's growth engine.
Uh, next we're gonna guide you
through mapping your customer journey, uh, to identify
what we call ascension points.
These are those crucial moments
where customers can really transition into becoming,
uh, business ambassadors.
Uh, whether that's by providing testimonials, whether
that's making referrals for new business, uh,
or whether it's best their services.
Uh, and finally, uh, this is a common question that we get,
uh, and I'm sure it's probably one
of yours right now as well.
And that's, what do I do with all of the SOPs
that Claude is generating?
How do I organize them
and how do I make them useful today for our team?
Uh, so those are the things
that we're covering in today's session.
It's quite a lot of information, um,
but excited that, uh, we're diving into it together.
And with that, I'm gonna hand over to Josh to get us started
with the five R's of customer excellence.
Awesome. Thank you, Midori.
And I'll, I'll speak to a little more of that.
Uh, before we dive into today's curriculum,
I just wanna pause for a moment
and acknowledge, um, the work that you've all already done.
Some of you're doing this again, um,
because what you've completed so far really matters.
So as she mentioned, up until this point, you've,
you've finished Foundation Week, you've gone through
multiple live sessions last week, worked hands-on
with Claude, and spent time learning how to actually operate
inside the tools, not just conceptually, but practically.
Um, you've explored things like projects versus chats,
artifacts, different ways of structuring work,
and how to interact with AI intentionally.
Uh, for some, this was familiar territory.
For others it was completely new.
But what's important is that everyone now has
been pulled into a, a shared baseline experience.
And that's certainly not accidental.
As Midori mentioned this,
this work only compounds when we're operating from a,
from a common foundation.
The real work and,
and value isn't just learning how to use an AI tool,
it's learning how to give it the right context.
And that's where the idea of the master prompt comes in.
The master prompt isn't just a collection of preferences
or style guides, it's a structured way
of giving AI the business context.
It needs to actually be useful.
So whether that's helping you generate something new,
improve something that already exists,
or document work that's never been documented
before, in some cases, you'll use it
to build things from scratch, like processes.
In other cases, you'll use it to pressure test
what already exists, which will surface gaps,
inconsistencies, or opportunities for improvement.
But both are valuable.
And what you're really doing is building
shared understanding between you and the system.
And that understanding is
what allows more advanced use cases, including automation,
to work for you later on.
Um, that foundation enables better prioritization,
better delegation,
and eventually real automation
that actually adds value instead of kind
of amplifying chaos or bad process.
So it's not about copying a template, it's about learning
how to apply structured thinking to your own business
with AI as a collaborator.
And that's what you're, you're starting to experience.
And, and that kind of thinking requires intention,
focus, and effort.
So it's, it's worth saying clearly that the work you've done
so far matters, and it's setting you up well
for, for what comes next.
And today, we're going to build on that foundation.
We're gonna walk through an overview of the five drivers
of customer excellence,
and we'll begin unpacking
how those show up in real operational workflows.
This sets the stage for the next phase of the program
where we move from, you know, understanding concepts
to systematically applying them kind of one area at a time.
So thank you all for the time, focus and effort.
You, you've already invested,
and now we'll kind of begin turning
that foundation into something durable, practical, and,
and valuable for your business.
So let's get into it. Okay.
Just keep in mind that there are six stages in the customer
lifecycle, and these stages represent the core process
of every organization.
The labels we use
for those stages may look a little different depending on
your situation, and that's okay.
What we're giving you are universal definitions that apply
across all businesses, even if the language needs
to be adjusted to fit your specific model.
For example, if you're a, a nonprofit, a sale
might not be a transaction at all.
It might be a donor relationship.
And the outcomes you create in subscription business,
it, it looks one way in professional services,
it looks different, but the structure is the same,
the expression is different.
And what matters is that you map these stages, honestly, to
how value actually flows in your organization.
So the stage we're focusing on next is delivery to success.
So this is about making sure your customers
or stakeholders are truly successful
after they engage with you.
It means measuring the right things,
supporting them in the right ways, and setting them up.
So their success drives future growth for your organization.
And this applies to everyone, whether you're small
or large, product-based, service-based, for-profit,
nonprofit, every organization
benefits from clearly understanding what success looks like
for its customers and how that success in turn
fuels long-term value and growth.
Now, as we zoom in on customer excellence,
specifically the idea of delivery to success,
this stage isn't just about fulfilling what you promised.
It's about making sure your customers are actually
successful, and
that their success becomes a growth engine for your business.
When that happens, a few important things follow naturally.
Customers stay longer, they get more value,
they advocate you, and they fuel sustainable growth.
So customer excellence is not accidental, it's designed,
and it comes from being clear on
what success really looks like for your customers,
measuring the right outcomes
and building systems
that consistently support those outcomes at scale.
The five Rs give us a clear way
to think about customer success and long-term growth.
The first is results.
Every customer relationship starts here.
We need to understand what success actually looks like
for our customers, their desired outcomes.
Sometimes we know this clearly, sometimes we think we know,
and sometimes we need to ask better questions
to truly understand the job, you know,
they're hiring our product or service to do.
The second is retention.
If we have customers, we want to keep them.
Retaining an existing customer is almost always easier
and more valuable than acquiring a new one.
That that means that we need to understand
what keeps customers with us
and measure retention intentionally.
The third is reviews.
When customers share their experiences publicly
or privately, it becomes a powerful driver of growth.
Reviews and testimonials matter at every stage
of a business, but they only work if they're real
and grounded in results that actually matter to customers.
The fourth, the, excuse me, the fourth R is referrals.
This is about turning customer satisfaction into advocacy.
We use NPS score surveys in this cohort,
and I will share, like, while surveys
and scores can be very useful insights, the,
the real measure, uh, is simple
and it's our customers actively referring others.
And are we set up to support and track that effectively?
The fifth R is repeat or returning customers.
That looks different depending on your business model,
but the idea is the same.
And that's customers come back, buy more,
or continue engaging with you over time.
This one is, is one of the strongest indicators
of real value being delivered.
So altogether, these five Rs give us a practical lens
for building customer excellence.
So they're areas, organizations I,
I have noticed often overlook
or they under optimize,
especially when rushing into automation.
So as we start to use AI
and automation, it's critical
that we focus on the outcomes that actually matter.
Um, when we do that, well, you know, results, referrals
and repeat business become natural byproducts.
So here I wanna give some examples and some ideas
and some universal metrics
that apply in each of these five areas.
Uh, to at least start your thinking.
You can absolutely ask Claude
for additional insights as well.
Um, but this is to just get us thinking.
So, uh, we have results in mind.
If it's a service business,
oftentimes we see things like project milestones hit
or problems resolved, or skills developed.
Those might be ways to, to kind measure results
for product business.
Uh, it's things like product performance
or potential user satisfaction
and the effectiveness of problem solving.
For experienced businesses, it's things like number
of memorable moments or the kinds of personal transformation
or goals achieved.
So there's certainly opportunity to level this up.
When it comes to retention service,
businesses could be measured
by things like contract renewals or ongoing engagements
or retainer agreements, product businesses.
It could be repeat purchases, subscription renewals,
and brand loyalty metrics.
For experienced businesses, it's return visits,
membership renewals, and continued participation.
For examples, I touched on
NPS scores already,
but the idea behind this is that you're, you're going
to have a certain number of people in your customer base
that are detractors
and you know, a number that are promoters.
And it's important to understand that if we have detractors,
that internal feedback informs strategic improvements
and process optimization.
This isn't something to be avoided, uh, it's something
to be recognized as valuable and embrace it.
I know we've had a, a couple detractors in,
in previous cohorts,
and it actually turned out when we kind of dug into the,
the nature of that feedback, that it, it wasn't
that the value didn't exist, it was that it was kind
of mismatched to the particular situation,
and the detraction turned into an actual positive referral
as a, as a result of sort of recognizing it
and addressing it head on.
So promoters results are testimonials,
case studies and success stories that are
invaluable in attracting new customers
and providing social proof.
So net promoter score is a valuable metric
best wielded alongside the, the metrics around retention
and return volume
and things like referrals in, in order to understand what's
actually being told to us.
So referrals are often something we struggle
to do effectively.
Yet, word of mouth will always be your most
powerful marketing channel.
Does anyone on the call want
to guess the number one reason in business?
People don't get referrals.
Anybody know, wanna put in the chat,
Christian?
Exactly. They don't ask.
That's not Josh and Power Labs saying that that is every,
uh, every inspirational book I've,
I've ever read on the matter.
That is the always the number one reason people
don't get referrals.
And what referrals look like will vary
depending on your business model.
Of course, as we can see here.
For, for service businesses, they often show up
as professional introductions, maybe client recommendations
or industry partners kind of sending people your way.
For product business, they, they tend to look like
personal recommendations, social sharing,
or perhaps affiliate relationships where
customers actively promote what they use.
And for experience-based businesses,
referrals are often driven by community.
So friends telling friends social proof,
and people wanting others
to have the same experience they did.
So different formats, same underlying principle,
and that is customers advocating on your behalf
because they saw real value.
That's why referrals can't be forced.
They're an outcome of delivering results
that actually matter.
So across all business types,
there are a few universal metrics worth paying attention to.
Um, referral rate, referral conversion, community
or audience growth.
Um, participation in advocacy or referral programs.
These metrics kind of help you understand,
not just if customers are happy,
but whether they're willing to put their reputation
behind you as a business.
And as we think about customer excellence,
referrals are a powerful signal.
When customers recommend you, it's often
because you help them succeed.
And that success is now sort of driving
your growth as a company.
Resale is about expanding relationships
with existing customers.
And in most businesses, this is one
of the most efficient ways to grow
because trust has already been established.
What resale looks like depends on your business.
Um, for service businesses, resale often shows up as upsells
to premium services and expanded scope
or additional service categories.
For product businesses, it can include cross-sales,
product upgrades, replenishment of consumables
or accessory purchases.
And for experience based businesses,
resale usually looks like premium experiences,
additional programs, or potentially extended memberships.
So again, different formats.
Same principle, customers choosing
to deepen the relationship
because they're seeing ongoing value.
So across all business types,
there are some universal metrics here to, to understand,
which would be expansion, revenue, purchase frequency,
average order value, and upgrade rates.
These metrics tell us whether customers see enough value
to continue investing, not because they're being pushed to,
but because the next step makes sense.
Resale, like referrals is an outcome of customer success.
And when customers are getting real results,
buying more becomes a natural progression,
not in any way a hard sell.
Maori, would you like to tee us up for a breakout session?
Yes. Thanks so much, Josh.
Thanks for sharing all of this information.
Uh, again, I just wanna acknowledge, as Josh had said,
that we've got a lot of diverse experiences in this cohort.
It includes everything from solopreneurs
to large organizations
and nonprofits, everything in between.
Um, but despite this variety, I'm really confident
that you all have a clear understanding of your customers
and your clients and how to meet their needs effectively.
So for the breakout that's coming up,
we're gonna take about 15 minutes
and work in groups of three or four, uh,
and really discuss the five Rs.
Um, and where you are strongest and where you are weakest.
Uh, I encourage you to apply, uh, the concept
of the five R's, even if the specific language, uh, you use,
say, in a nonprofit
or a recruitment agency, um, might be different just so
that we have this sort of universal kind of experience
that we can dive into, uh, together.
So, you know, it may be the case
that you're doing a great job of delivering results, uh,
but you can't seem to get those, uh, reviews from clients.
Or maybe you're getting referrals,
but having trouble retaining those as ongoing customers.
Uh, so I am going to, uh, place in,
um, the chat, and I will also just get you all set up again,
if we could do maybe a lightning round where we go through,
um, your strongest and your weakest of the five Rs.
And then after everyone has had a chance to kind of talk it
through, um, from there we can really, uh, dive deeply
because I think it'll be really interesting
to learn more from each other as we hear, uh, you know, uh,
our colleagues sort of strengths.
Uh, there'll, there'll be things
that I think you all can apply
to your own experiences as well.
So just getting us set up
here, here we go.
Opening the rooms.
Uh, and you don't have to worry about,
uh, keeping track of time.
You'll automatically be added back in about
15 minutes or so.
All right?
All right. Uh, are you gonna be, uh,
joining a breakout today or
Probably not. Okay.
I'll let I, I like, I like the setup.
I, I do want people to, you know,
'cause what hap I mean, it, I will like, as we go
through it, but maybe more when people are kind
of in the groove a little bit more.
Because what I've noticed is like, I do want people
to get value from, like, let's say they're on
with somebody who's like, oh, I'm, I'm making it up,
but like, I crush with referrals.
This is how I do it.
I want an opportunity in like an open discussion
for that to take place.
And I, I don't want to interrupt that, but it,
whenever I do, by the way, if you want to, it's always like,
all I ended up doing was like, Hey guys,
I'm just a fly on the wall.
I'm just sort of popping into different rooms,
so just act like I'm not even here and I mute myself.
Yeah. Um, sometimes when it's done, I'll add, like,
if they go around and everybody knows
and they've had a discussion, then I can get involved.
But typically I just want them to kind of connect with them
to have that like, piece of community.
Mm-hmm. What fell?
Oh, that's my, I was presenting
and then something fell on my desk.
Just gonna run to the washroom
and I'll be back in one sec.
Yeah, I'll be, I'm gonna mute,
I'm gonna turn the camera off and mute myself
and I'll, I'll be kind of paying attention,
but I'll, I'll be here if you need me. Just say something.
Sounds good. Thanks.
Hi, Midori. I'm having internet problems.
I got bounced out. I think I'm back in.
I don't know if it's too late to get in a group.
Ah, sorry to hear about that. Okay.
Uh, adding you, I'm gonna add you now.
Thank you.
Hello. Hello.
Nobody joined my room. I guess I to find another one.
Let me, uh, let me just, uh, add you into, all right,
Thanks.
There you go.
Welcoming folks back.
Hope you had a nice, uh, chance to connect there.
I love the smiles on everyone's faces as we come back,
so hopefully they weren't talking about us.
Naori.
Uh, we would really love to hear, uh, some insights.
So I'd love to understand whether there were some themes
that emerged, uh, across, uh, folks experience.
Uh, or one thing that, um, you heard
that might really matter in, in identifying
where these important parts are
that you can apply to your own business.
Uh, so, um, anyone who wants to unmute, uh, speak that,
uh, insight into the room.
Uh, otherwise, uh, chat is also another option
and we can read some of those.
Yeah, I, I can do do something.
We, we have two, uh, let's say two services mainly.
One is a representative service
that is a very standardized service,
and, uh, they need to label, uh,
for the Swiss market
where we are the representative for them.
So it's a liable legal, uh, person.
And, um, this, this requires also in the production process
and, uh, labeling process, uh, changes.
So you, the retention is very high because the people, uh,
or the managers and companies don't want to change.
And, uh, on the other side, we are, uh,
have a consulting, um, business.
We sell mainly little packages for, uh,
gap assessments for regulatory conformity in the medical
device, uh, sector.
And, um, you could, uh, yeah, imaging
a first is a gap assessment,
and then we fill the gaps in an implementation project.
But this is, uh, seldom, uh, we help them
to turn out to, to not be a medical device so
unregulated, so they don't need us anymore.
That's, uh, one end.
And the, uh, the other is, um, they do it themselves
because, uh, they think they can do it better.
Sometimes they come back, uh,
two years later and they failed.
But this is not, uh, a business model. Mm-hmm.
So, yeah, that, that's, uh,
quite a difference in these two, two, uh, service part.
And, and in light of wanting to focus on one thing, Benny,
of course, uh, for all of you,
if you're in the same predicament, use Claude
to unpack this a bit.
It, it could start to become very, very clear.
'cause there's context I won't have.
But, um, in the spirit of just asking a question
that might be helpful, um, initially, which one
of those do you feel like you want
to focus on while you're here?
You know, during the cohort?
Yes. Oh, which,
which one are you thinking? Are you thinking,
Sorry, you, you are asking
Swiss market that requires the production
or the consulting side?
Sorry.
Yeah. Um, oh, this is a political question.
Uh, because, um, the, the standardized service might end
in 28 due to a, uh, an election
or public rotation in Switzerland.
And, um, we will assign to the EU again,
because we are an island at the moment, uh,
this is very complicated.
Uh, I don't go into the details.
That's why we need to increase our consulting business.
Yeah. And that's my focus.
Okay, good. That's, that's great.
By the way, give that information to AI as well.
Yeah, I did. This
Is, this is why I will be focusing on the consulting
because of those political things, if it'll be interesting
to see if, uh, it's aware.
Um, awesome.
Um, do you, does anybody else wanna share? Okay.
Tim wrote out here, Tim strongest results,
resale weakest referrals review.
Can I ask Tim, is it because you're not asking
or, um, just kind
of like not producing at the level it could
or should what you have in place right now?
I think we, we, I mean, generally we have great results
and we, um, sort of, um, get the situation
where we land at a customer
and then expand with like future consulting projects.
Yep. Um, but somehow we don't really use these good results
that we have in order to Yeah.
Package them into good use cases for advertisement,
for sales, et cetera.
And, um, also get, get really qualitative, uh,
reviews from Yeah.
Key stakeholders, so to say.
And yeah, as I said, the retention is kind of difficult
for the, for the consulting, uh, service right now,
but make might change for future products like education.
Yeah.
Gotcha. Okay, well, thank you for sharing.
And I think, I think
as we get into mapping the customer journey, right,
the key points that we're about to go through, I think
that's gonna be really helpful for you.
But the first part for all of you is,
is just to get the clarity right.
Uh, it's like Jim Collins, like, like, let's just,
this is what a fact is.
Like this is the way that it is. There's no shame in that.
Um, if you don't have clarity, you know, there's,
there's nothing to improve.
So let's dive in to mapping the customer journey.
So one of the most important parts of mapping
the customer journey is recognizing that literally have
to battle is, is simply remembering to ask
as we kind of joked before.
But, um, I know personally I've managed sales teams in the
past, and there was just a very clear pattern
of, you know, what I call
aha moments in, in the customer journey.
And I can tell you that the people who
received the most referrals were not necessarily the top
producer or the most senior person.
They were the ones who asked every single
time at the right moment.
So not occasionally, not only when it felt perfect with the,
the customer every single time.
And in my experience, um, the delta
of always asking will usually become the 80 20 rule
where kind of 80% of your referrals end up coming from 20%
of the customers that just absolutely
champion your product or service.
I don't know if you all are, are like me in that way,
but I've certainly seen it play out that way.
Um, most customers who are happy
are actually willing to refer.
They just aren't pro, you know, prompted to do so.
People are far more likely
to share negative experiences on their own,
but positive experiences often stay silent
unless we create a space for them.
In any team, you'll also see a, you know,
natural variation.
Some people instinctively remember to ask for referrals
or reviews, others don't, not because they don't care, but
because it's just not top of mind in the moment.
That's why this can, this,
this can't rely on a person or memory.
It has to be process driven.
So when we map the customer journey properly,
we can identify the moments that matter most, um,
at the points where value has clearly been delivered,
and it makes sense to ask at that moment,
then we build that into process.
So it happens consistently.
The goal is to create a system that makes asking automatic,
and, and that's what you're going to, to focus on
as we work through this.
Okay? So we're going to tackle delivery
to success in three clear parts,
and each one builds on the last, first,
we'll we'll map the customer journey using the prompt,
you'll, you'll think through the, the full delivery
to success experience from the customer's point of view.
And the goal here is to identify the, the key touch points
and the ascension points, the moments
where value is delivered, trust is built,
and the relationship can naturally deepen.
This is where the, the deep thinking comes in.
You know, what, what do those moments
look like in your business?
Where do customers get the most value?
And where are their opportunities to improve experience
or guide them forward?
You've all now gone through the, the thinking
and the prompts and the questions in the conversation
that kind of goes back and forth.
So identifying those key touch points
and ascension points throughout the delivery
to success stage will be incredibly valuable for you
to create process.
Second, we will create level one and level two SOPs.
Once the journey is clear, we'll document the core process.
Level one gives you the high level blue blueprint.
The, the visual overview of, of how the process works end
to end level two adds structure
and clarity to the major steps within that flow.
This is valuable even if parts of your delivery rely on
external partners today, for example, um,
mapping the process helps you understand handoffs
responsibilities and quality checkpoints,
and it also prepares you for the future if certain parts
of the process eventually move in-house as you scale.
Third will create a priority implementation matrix.
As you start generating ideas, insights, and,
and opportunities, the the list can grow very quickly.
Um, and, and this matrix will help you decide
what to implement first.
So focusing on actions that are high impact
and relatively low effort, you'll use this
to prioritize whether you're working solo with a,
a small team or across a larger organization.
And it becomes a, a living tool that you can return to
as new ideas emerge.
So you're, you're always focused on
what will move the needle most.
So by the end of this, you, you won't just have ideas,
you'll have structure, clarity,
and a way to turn insight into action.
The customer journey is, is kind of the foundation
for everything we're about to do.
Before we dive into to processes
or automation, we need
to clearly map the journey your customers go through,
and more importantly, identify the key stages
and ascension points along that journey.
Ascension points are the moments
where customers are most likely to take meaningful action.
These are points where they're naturally inclined to
share a testimonial or review, refer others,
upgrade or deepen their engagement,
and become advocates or ambassadors for your brand.
Potentially. Often businesses receive reviews
or referrals kind of randomly, you know,
that's certainly better than nothing,
but it's not intentional.
And what we wanna understand is when those moments are most
likely to occur within your specific delivery cycle,
not every moment is the right moment to ask.
Early in the journey, customers may still be learning,
adjusting, or even experiencing some friction, a
as they adapt, like the natural s-curve in business.
So asking for referrals or reviews too early
before value is kind of fully realized,
usually doesn't work at the level that it could or should.
And so the real opportunity comes when customers begin
to experience results.
When value is clear, confidence is high,
and progress is visible to that customer, um, they're,
they're far more willing to recommend you
expand the relationship or sort of advocate on your behalf.
This will look differently for every business.
So the goal here isn't to copy a template, it's
to understand your journey
and identify where those moments naturally occur.
Once we have that clarity,
everything else becomes easier to design.
We can then place the right actions, prompts,
and systems at the right points in the journey instead
of just like guessing or relying on chance.
And that's why mapping the customer journey comes first.
It gives you all the context needed to kind
of build everything that follows.
So, um, I'm gonna stop sharing
and I'm gonna, I'm gonna open up the prompts right here,
and I'm just gonna go over all of this with you
so we can explore them and discuss it a little bit.
Okay. Can you see my screen session four here? Okay.
So the five Rs.
When we wrap this live session, uh,
the first thing you're going to do is add the five Rs
of customer excellence to your master prompt.
The purpose of this is simple but powerful.
You're giving Claude a shared mental model for
what customer success actually means in your business.
So once the five Rs are part of your master prompt,
Claude can consistently think with you
and for you across results, retention, reviews,
referrals, and resale.
So this ensures that every process you build, every SOP
that you document and every improvement
that you explore is aligned to the outcomes
that actually drive growth.
From a a practical standpoint, this is a quick step.
You'll open your master prompt project under the files,
you'll just click the, the plus button, add text content
and label it the five Rs,
and then just paste the framework that you,
you see here on the doc.
That's it. But
what you're really doing is upgrading Claude from a general
assistant into a customer excellence aware
partner for your business.
Once that's in place, you'll move into running the delivery
to success assessment.
So you'll, you know, it's, it's a, it's a big prompt,
but you'll copy and paste this prompt
and create a new chat titled Delivery to Success Assessment.
This assessment is designed to help you slow down
and take a clear objective look at where your business
actually stands today across each of these five Rs.
So instead of operating on like assumptions
or gut feel, you will evaluate what's truly happening.
Like it's just like the breakout room, what's working well,
what's inconsistent,
and where there are real gaps in your customer experience.
As you work through it, you'll begin to see patterns emerge.
Some areas may already be strong and,
and simply need refinement.
Others may be underdeveloped
or happening by accident rather than by design.
The goal isn't to judge
or overwhelm you, it's to just surface clarity.
One of the most important outcomes
of this assessment is focus, rather than trying to
improve everything at once, you'll identify which
of the five Rs represent the biggest opportunity
for your impact right now.
And that'll allow you to prioritize intelligently
and avoid kind of spreading your efforts too thin.
So the, the output
of this work isn't just insight, it's direction.
It gives you a, a, a baseline you can measure over time, uh,
helps inform what to implement first
and provides Claude with richer content about your business
so it can support you more effectively as you kind
of design processes, SOPs, and all workflows going forward.
So that foundation will, will carry
through everything we do next
and will directly shape
how you apply the work in the sessions ahead
after you complete the assessment.
The next step is
to map your customer journey in a very focused way.
So this step, as you can see here, it it, it uses a, um,
a simpler, uh, prompt,
but it's intentionally designed to be interactive.
Instead of Claude generating something in isolation,
it will ask you a series of thoughtful questions
to help surface how your customer journey actually works
today from delivery all the way through success.
At this point, Claude already has important context.
You've added the five to your master prompt,
and you've completed the assessment,
which means the project now understands
how you think about customer outcomes, retention reviews,
referrals and resale.
And with that founda, uh, foundation in place, it's ready
to help you build a meaningful, accurate picture
of your delivery to success journey.
So you'll, you'll do this in a separate chat
inside your master prompt, uh, titled,
you know, delivery to Success.
You can put customer journey and parentheses in that chat.
Claude will ask you to be very specific about which product
or service you are analyzing.
And this is that important constraint will, will continue to
bring up here as a caution,
because many of you will, will naturally want to
map multiple products, offers, or services.
Um, trust me, that instinct makes sense.
However, best practice is to just start with one,
choose a, a single product
or service that is core to your business
or maybe represents a meaningful portion
of your revenue or impact.
And by narrowing your focus, you'll get a clearer,
more usable customer journey map instead of something
that's more overly broad or potentially abstract.
And once that journey is mapped well for one offering,
it becomes much easier to then replicate
or adopt the process later
for additional products or services.
So individual focus here sets you up
for much stronger outcomes as we continue to build.
Okay, so similar to the last assessment,
after you complete the customer journey work,
the next thing you'll move into is creating SOPs
for delivery to success.
This is where everything you've done so far starts
to turn into something tangible.
So up until this point, you've been building context,
you've defined the five Rs, you've completed an assessment,
you've mapped the customer journey.
Now we're, we're going to use all of that context
to create real usable process documentation, not theory,
not abstractions,
but something you could actually hand to other team members.
And the goal is twofold.
First, we want to create a level one SOP,
which is the high level map of your
delivery to success process.
This is the, um, what happens in what order view
it shows the, the major stages, the, the start point,
the endpoint, and kind of how value moves
through your organization after a customer says yes.
Second, we wanna create level two SOPs, which act
as blueprints for the functional areas inside
that level one process.
These don't go into like task by task instructions yet.
Instead they clarify ownership inputs, outputs,
handoffs, and quality checkpoints.
So think of level two as the, the structural framing
that sort of makes future automation, delegation,
or optimization possible.
The important thing to understand is
that Claude is not starting from scratch here.
And by the time you run these prompts,
it already has a lot of context.
It understands your business
through the master prompt understands the five Rs,
it understands your delivery to success assessment,
and it understands your customer journey.
And that's why the output at this stage is
dramatically better than what we all know,
as I'll say generic SOPs.
So how this actually works in practice is you'll,
you'll do all of this in one continuous chat,
the same chat you used for the Delivery
to success assessment.
Uh, this matters because Claude is, is kind of building
on the, the full conversation history,
and then you'll run these three prompts, just like you did,
um, last time, um, one at a time and just take it through.
So, uh, and then a reminder on the last question here,
do these SOPs seem over-engineered
for a company the size of mine?
Okay, so this will happen a lot, guys, we're,
you can get an enterprise level plan for
what you're looking to accomplish.
You might be a solopreneur, you might have, uh, you know,
uh, tenor or less employees, right?
That is not going to be appropriate.
And that is a constant part of the iterative process with ai
because it'll just give you a, a plan for a, a,
a 100 person company, and that's not going to help you.
So if you do that, if the answer is yes, a lot of times
with ai, like Claude will suggest what to simply remove
and then update the artifacts accordingly.
This step's critical
because small teams, as I mentioned,
like you don't need enterprise level complexity.
Complexity is the of execution.
And having a right sized process is actually
what is going to get used.
And so by the end of like prompt three here,
you'll have SOPs that are appropriate for
whatever current stage you are at,
not some idolized future version of
what your business could be.
And, and once the SOPs are finalized,
you'll download the artifacts
or use copy to project to add them if, if you do it
that way, to, to your project knowledge.
And, and this ensures that Claude can kind
of reference going forward, which becomes incredibly
powerful as you move into sort of prioritization automation
and sort of AI assisted execution later on.
The final piece of this, um,
you'll work on is creating your
priority implementation matrix.
So up to this point, you've, you've generated a lot
of insight assessments, customer journey maps and SOPs.
Now that's very powerful.
Um, and you all might see that,
but it, it can also feel like a lot, it, it,
it's a lot that it will output.
So the, the purpose of the priority implementation matrix is
to turn all of that insight into just very
clear execution focus.
And so this matrix will actually give you a structured way
to decide what to implement first based on impact.
And, you know, complexity, not intuition or urgency or,
or whatever kind of feels right in the moment, which a lot
of people just tend to operate their business that way.
So to do this, you'll, you'll open a new chat
inside your master prompt project, label it
priority implementation matrix.
Um, um, this is important
'cause this chat becomes a living workspace
that you'll return to throughout the cohort.
So once you, you run the prompt, Claude will, you know,
look across your sale to delivery assessment, your delivery
to success assessment, the processes
and gaps you've already identified.
From there, it will, will generate a simple
but powerful matrix that organizes potential improvements by
impact, like high, medium, low,
and then complexity, low, medium, high.
And the, the result will be a, a, a clear visual table
that shows you where to start, like what to tackle next
and what belongs in the future.
And one important habit, uh, to build here,
like once you've created this chat, um,
I would suggest starring it.
Um, you can do this inside the chat,
or if you're in your project, you can just go
to the little dots on the side of the chat.
If you star any of your chats,
that will keep it pinned at the top.
So it's easy to find.
You certainly don't have to do that
because it's gonna be named appropriately.
Um, but it's just a suggestion as you'll be kind
of returning to this matrix repeatedly as you understand,
uh, or as your understanding deepens,
as your sort of business evolves.
So think of the priority implementation matrix as kind
of the bridge between strategy
and execution, if that makes sense.
It's, um, it ensures
that all the work you're doing translates into focused
action and not overwhelm.
And that's why we introduced it now
and kind of continue refining it as we move forward.
Okay. So hopefully you all have a clear understanding
after me just kind of going over
everything at a high level there.
And of course, there are simple
step-by-step directions up here, literally just going over
everything that I just went over with you, um,
on these docs, um, going over the purpose as well as exactly
what to do as you go through them.
And, um, we will get
to questions if you have them in the end,
but for now, I will get back into the lesson just to, um,
continue with part three here.
Okay.
Alright. So we're working with what we call the,
the four level of SOPs.
And this framework is intentionally designed to kind
of make process creation useful
at every level of the organization.
So from leadership down to execution at a high level,
each SOP um, level serves a different purpose
and audience, and together they create clarity, alignment,
and then leverage.
So level one SOPs are your, your core process views.
Level two SOPs are your blueprints.
Level three SOPs move into step-by-step guides.
And level four SOPs are the supporting assets.
So for this cohort, we're intentionally kind
of focusing on level one and level two.
The reason is simple, and that's without a clear process map
and functional blueprint detailed instructions
and templates just don't scale well.
And when you have level one
and level two in place, level three
and four just become far easier
and far more effective to then create later on.
So this approach also sets you up powerfully for the future.
So whether you're, you're delegating work to,
to people supporting teams with AI
or moving toward more advanced automation,
having clear level one
and level two SOPs gives you the structure needed to do
that responsibly and effectively.
And that's why we start here
and why these four levels matter.
So this slide shows an example of how the, the four levels
of SOPs work together as a, a single system rather than kind
of like isolated documents.
You know, for our company, just as a, a very simple
reference at the top,
you have level one, the the core process.
So this represents the, the full end-to-end view
of a major stage in your business.
This is, uh,
in this case something like delivery to success.
So for our live cohort experience that you're in,
from there, we move into level two blueprints.
So blueprints break that core process into functional areas
or major components.
So these are the, the pieces of the process that the teams
or owners are responsible for.
Next is level three, which is guides, guides,
zoom in even further
and explain how specific activities are actually executed.
This is where you get step-by-step instructions
for kind of doing the work.
So how something is run, delivered,
or completed on a reoccurring basis.
Level three is
what enables consistency across people and time.
And finally, level four is, is tools and templates.
These are kind of the, the practical resources used to
execute guide templates, checklists, scripts,
calculators, documents, whatever it may be.
Um, level four doesn't define the process, it supports it.
So if anyone didn't already figure out, like,
we're using Gamma for the generation of these slides, both
to challenge ourselves by using an AI enabled tool,
but also just to model that for you
as an example in this case.
Okay, this slide captures the important idea.
Um, SOP creation is an iterative cycle,
not a one-time event.
So there are really three simple steps
in how we approach this.
First is create.
So we start by letting Claude do the initial heavy
lifting across this cohort.
Everyone's business is different, so different sizes, levels
of complexity and stages of maturity.
The goal here isn't to handcraft perfect
documentation from scratch.
The goal is to get just a solid
first version on the page quickly.
Claude helps you kind of generate level one core processes
and level two blueprints, so you're not kind
of staring at a blank page.
Second is review.
So once those artifacts get generated, your
responsibility is to review them
and then make sure that they generally make sense.
I want to clarify because some people get, when they have
to give deep thought in their company,
like you will do in this cohort, um, for a lack
of a better term, they get stuck whether it's, I don't know,
the answer to this question, or I don't have that data,
or, you know, you're potentially overthinking it.
So I I I do want to clarify that you, you absolutely want
to give deep thought here, right?
Um, but you're not expected to just be perfect.
Like you're, you're not, you, you, you are expected
to look at anything, you know, with a critical eye
and ask yourself like, is this directionally right?
Does this reflect how our business actually works today?
Um, this review setup is
what turns like generic output into something useful.
And so the, the third is, is correct.
If something is out of order, missing
or inaccurate, uh, you know, you don't start over, you reply
to Claude and correct it.
You tell it what's wrong or what's, what needs adjusting.
And that back and forth is, is kind of part of the process.
You can also decide to flag something and,
and come back to it later.
Both approaches are valid.
Um, the key thing to understand is that this is not a one
and done right.
The, the, the thirst pass gets you moving
and iteration is, is what makes it better.
So over time, as you review these SOPs with yourself
and your team, apply them in the real world
and layer in new insights, you'll continue refining them.
And each cycle makes the documentation more accurate,
more useful, and more aligned with
how your business actually operates.
So that's the mindset we we want you to adopt here.
It's create review, correct and repeat.
So we talked about the
implementation priority matrix already.
Um, it's the starting point for beginning
to think about implementing recommendations that come up.
You've already gotten a lot of recommendations, right?
Claude is super helpful in that regard.
It likes to be super helpful.
Um, however, as I I keep saying, you can't do it all if,
whether you're one person
or you have a a big staff, you can't do it all right away.
So, so let's start
to bring those suggestions back into the priority matrix,
get that put into place,
and then be prepared to sort of revisit that for purposes
of keeping ourselves organized.
Um, we walk through the implementation matrix prompt earlier
and now when it comes to organizing your SOPs as a company,
I think we touched on this a bit,
but let's talk about this for a moment
and how this can actually apply for you and your company.
So organizing SOPs is a big topic
and there's certainly a lot of options here.
Um, you know, for us in the cohort for purposes
of demonstration, we've used clawed project files
as the thing we want to, to put our SOPs in,
but in, in real world use, um, there's lots of options for
how we we go about archiving
and sort of documenting our SOPs.
So there are some category examples, um,
that include organizational knowledge management solutions.
That could be things like notion.
I know a lot of us here maybe have used Notion, those of us
that have been working with, you know,
Tiago over the past few years.
Notion's been a big part of the Forte Lab stuff and,
and building a Second Brain.
There's other examples as well.
Um, I'll say a good rule of thumb here is to
say those are potentially good options
for you if you already use them.
Like that's the, that's the simplest way.
First question is to say, what does your team already use
and find effective?
That's typically a great place to start at Empower Labs.
We're, we're sort of Google centric, so all
of our documentation ends up in Google Drive.
Um, we have used Notion in the past.
Um, now currently we use, um,
our own stage three software for this.
Um, and you all will be getting access to that as well.
And so there, there's lots of opportunities here.
You know, as you can see,
organizational management solutions are good.
If you want those, uh, integrated into your,
your broader knowledge base, cloud storage like Google or,
or OneDrive and Dropbox and, and many, many like that.
If you're just starting that, that's typically a,
a very good solution.
And again, if your team's already embedded into one
of those things, that's a good opportunity for you.
It's the, the simplest and,
and kind of most familiar,
there's also specialized software.
Um, so there's things like Process Street, um, you know,
again, we, we have our own internal software stage three
that we'll be sharing with you all in order to,
to do this if you so choose, um, as you continue building,
um, some of you may already have access to it.
Um, but these are certainly useful if you need advanced
workflow automation or approval processes.
If you want more advanced analytics or workflows
and process completion, you know, get complex
or multi-step processes require tracking, um,
and more if you're, you're sort of looking
to invest in something that's sort of beyond the
original options, like an ERP for example.
So those are some examples of of how to store
and organize your SOPs for you to just be thinking about.
I will briefly just
'cause I have, um, access to it, um,
notion is a, it's a really good tool.
We used to use it
and so I'll share how we did this internally
with the program that you're a part of, just
so you could all could see some eyeballs on it.
Um, notion it's a great tool, it's very user friendly
and it's very, very easy for for small teams
to, to kind of use.
I will say in full transparency, I am not aware of
any large companies.
Uh, we've worked with a lot of large companies,
whether it's 50, a hundred, 500 to a few thousand,
I don't know any, I'll call it
enterprise companies using Notion.
But it is an incredibly powerful tool
to just store your SOPs in the, the,
the setting that we're discussing.
So, um, as you can see as we go through in power,
this is literally the cohort that you're in.
So market to lead, lead to sale, sale to delivery
and delivery to success is
what we're covering today for you to see.
So this is the name. It shows exactly kind of what it is.
It stores your SOPs, checklists, everything right here
for your, your team to be able to view very, very simply.
Um, it creates, um, everything from the frequency of
what it's done and it creates the RACI chart,
which is responsible, accountable, consulted,
and informed as well
as the last time these things were edited.
So this is just a high level version of, we used
to use this internally for you to see as an example of
how we stored our SOPs.
And then we have since transitioned to stage three.
I'm not gonna share that right now.
Um, not because I don't want to, but uh, just
because you all don't have access to it yet.
So I don't necessarily want to go in
and just start going through a software that none of you
or potentially a small amount of you have had access to.
So with that said, um,
I'd like to open it up for some questions.
So we covered a lot, of course.
This session is recorded and we're doing some deep work,
but of, of everything that we discussed for today in sort
of mapping your delivery to success, what, um,
what questions do you have?
Um, you can raise your hand or attempt to raise your hand.
We will, we will call on you
and make sure we, we, we get you squared away.
Um, Christian, uh, you just briefly,
'cause I'm looking at it, you asked what was your reason
for going away from Notion?
Uh, honestly, um, I guess the simple answer to that,
Christian was that it's, um, you know,
Hayden developed stage three, I think it's our,
it's eternally himself.
It's literally called stage three
because potentially wherever you're at, the goal is
to go from stage one to two and two to three.
So he, he created stage three
because there wasn't a great option
to store your master prompt.
Number one, share access to everyone on your team,
as you will all see it.
There's a variety of ways to do it. It's a bit clunky.
Um, so this streamlines that process
and it, it, it has everything from your SOPs
and process as well as RACI charts.
So it was just an internal solution.
And by the way, it was created with, uh,
mostly AI vibe coding.
So, uh, it's incredibly valuable, uh, for clarity.
You'll all get access to it at a certain point
so you can start sharing on it.
Um, but we're certainly not going to tell people you have
to use our software,
but that's kind of why it was created Christian and,
and kind of why we transitioned from
Notion, if that answers your question.
Okay. Thank you. Notion is a, is an incredible tool though.
Again, we, I, uh, I can share that even, uh,
if you guys in in circle, if you're like, Hey,
could you share the, the notion template, happy to do that.
We certainly used it for the exact program
that you're in right now, our live cohorts.
Um, and just so you all can just have a,
a view of what that could look like.
Um, now certainly we're, you know,
we're a small company, we're 10 people.
Um, it could look much more complex relative
to your organization and, and what that looks like for you.
But happy to, to share any
and all resources that we have if helpful.
I have a question, uh, regarding existing documentation.
As, as mentioned, uh, sometime before
or the last, uh, session,
we have a quality management system with a lot of SOPs
and, uh, work instructions and, and templates.
And, um, I wonder if, um, I can also
deliver them to plot to use it, uh,
when asking these questions
because, um, this is difficult to match.
That's one thing. And the other thing is we have, uh,
very distinct, uh, customer journey maps, uh,
done a year ago.
Mm-hmm. Uh, for different target groups or, uh, ICPs.
And, um, is it possible also
to just upload such information
or sh should I pick out the relevant information
to answer the questions?
Yeah, good question. Um, I always like to preface, uh,
in business and life, there's no one way to do anything.
Um, however, I would suggest you do that.
Now, this isn't exactly how you could do it,
but here's what I would do
to explore making sure you get the most out of it.
So you, you already have a knowledge base, which is great.
I recommend that you run the assessment
as is without your current knowledge base.
It's just a recommendation.
I recommend that you do that at the end
of the assessment when you have artifacts
and outputs and SOPs.
I would then take your information that you already have
because you've never run an assessment like this to sort
of understand your process.
And then I would say, I would tell Claude this is, um,
now that we're done with this assessment, take all
of my previous knowledge documentation
and see if there's any knowledge gaps of the assessment
that you just ran that need to be adjusted.
Or is there something that maybe I am not seeing
that this changes any of the outputs that you just did
for delivery to success?
And I would have that conversation, Benny, um,
because only you are going to know what that's going
to look like specifically.
But I would, I would, I would run data on data no different
than me suggesting to like Christina
and Tim, if they sort of run the exact same assessment
and then they, you know, Tim gives Christina his,
and they, they just go, this is Tim's assessment.
I wanna under, I want you to find the discrepancies.
And then that is a very powerful conversation.
Now you're doing it data to data,
but at that point you will have a few options.
It, it could either point out, well,
after looking at your previous knowledge documentation,
there's some things that you didn't make me aware,
some context perhaps.
And this is a really big thing to consider.
And you will start that dialogue
before you sort of revise your artifacts as,
let's call them finished products
for the sake of the exercise.
So that's what I recommend.
Um, there's also, you know, you could change the orders,
you could start with your knowledge documents as well.
There's a variety of ways to get to the same output,
but that's, um, how I may explore doing that if I were you.
Very good point, thank you.
Of course. I would hope anybody else.
Yeah, go ahead Montgomery.
My question touches on what you just mentioned,
but if we were to go back
and, uh, attempt to modify an SOP mm-hmm.
Is it best practice to go back into that specific chat
versus what may have happened
after the fact in the general project,
which has probably taken into context other SOPs
and delivery systems?
What, what's, what do you recommend?
Yeah, um, so I think someone asked this in circle two
by the way that I answered it, is if you're going to,
this is the editor of process, right?
So let's say something changes doesn't matter,
in this case it's delivery to success for today's session.
But yeah, if you're going, and you've already done this,
so whether that's something's changed in my company, um,
it's a new product, like whatever the, the output, right?
I suggest, and I think I, I said this in circles,
I suggest just going back to the chat
because it's already produced in artifact, right?
So for example, if, you know, like Benny,
for example, mentioned earlier in the session
that it's pretty clear that he,
because of out things outside of his control,
he's gonna be focusing on the consulting side for the,
the medical device companies, right?
Let's say that's, that's my thing I'm focusing on
when he does that, he'll already have an artifact right at
the end of whatever you're sort of referencing to go off of
and say, Hey, this finalized artifact has some new details
that I want to explore revisions.
So the last I did this, what's changed is A, B, C,
and D, and that's created different outcome.
Of course I'm making this up.
Um, but you at that, at that point, it,
it will just be more of like a prompt.
And then of course you may need to provide clarity just
to make sure that Claude has an understanding.
But after that you can essentially just say,
revise my current artifact including A, B, C,
and D, whatever that looks like for you specifically.
And then it will just output a revised artifact
with your revisions changes.
This, this happens all the time, by the way.
Like I I, you, you get new people in your company, right?
Like you're, everything changes in your org chart.
This is a constant iterative process.
You can just sort of go back.
And for me, the easy way, if you all haven't seen this yet,
like every time you create an artifact, it's archived.
So in Claude, it'll show you, if you're in delivery
to success, it'll show you previous archives.
That's why in naming inside Claude, it is good
to potentially put the date, you know,
this is kinda like the first time you're doing this
and a lot of people are starting again.
So that might not be as helpful in this moment,
but that's what I would suggest.
Montgomery just sort of going in, revising the work
that you've already done,
and then that way you just get the new artifact
and then you can just take, go over it in current,
let's say deliver to success.
Just save over that
and delete the old version in your actual
master prompt for context.
Aren't you missing any other pieces
that may have been affected like that?
For example, if in your case someone
went from one department to another,
they went from the success to retention
and now it's not gonna reflect that
that process has changed.
'cause you're going back to this first iteration of SOP, not
what you have, what I may have
done two or three weeks from now.
How does it know that?
I would think that going into a new chat
with all the history in the rear view mirror saying,
attached is my SOP from January 1st,
please update with X, Y, z.
Wouldn't it look at everything versus just Sure.
Again, a again, in, if you're in a chat, let's say you,
I mean you, you all will get to a point
where you'll have 10 artifacts of the same thing, right?
It's the iterative process. If you're in that chat,
it does use that whole chat for reference so that the,
the negative to that would be
that your context window could run out of space, right?
Your tokens. And so yes, if you all have
to start a new chat, you all might run into
that in this cohort.
The the simple thing is like, hey, take this
defined artifact, start a new chat,
and I'm, my goal is to whatever your,
your prompt is to just pick it up.
So whether you're, you're changing it, adding
or you, you have to do that
because you've hit your token limits.
I would say like, whatever you're comfortable with,
Montgomery, I mean, I typically just go back to the artifact
because it's finalized in whatever chat,
and I'll just make the revisions from there.
Um, but absolutely you can take the artifact
and hey, um, this is the finalized artifact
and I wanna start a new chat to
whatever your desired outcome is.
There's, that is not wrong.
There's just, you know, there's no one approach.
A dumb question. Does Claude then take into consideration
the other chat context as part of the whole LLM
or does it just stay within that specific chat?
Yeah, the chat spec, it will,
it will take your master prompt PR like project knowledge
into consideration, but it, it,
it won't necessarily take all the consideration.
It, it'll, it'll be just the one chat
that you're in plus got it.
All of your documents. And,
and you know, this is, this is actually something
we're working on right now in stage three.
This is actually the coolest feature, um, currently,
like if you, for example, if you integrate to Google Drive,
um, your SOPs, I notice like
they can update automatically from Claude to Google.
Um, but I don't know if anybody's like me.
I just don't, I can't count on that
because I know that when it comes to integrations,
like you'll be like, oh, I updated my marketing or my sales,
and you just sort of rely on that
and then it doesn't do that.
And so actually what we're working on now is in stage three,
there's the LLM portion, which is just a chat bot.
Um, it currently uses Gemini,
but in that, if you, if you're in a chat and,
and any part of your master prompt, if you're like,
I have now replaced Midori with Josh,
who is our new co-facilitator and,
and these type of roles in the chat,
I can hit update everything in all
of my project knowledge in my master prompt everywhere.
And it will do that. It's gonna be
developed later in February.
It's, it's on the, the timeline for this month.
It doesn't currently do that,
but when it does do that, I think it'll make it,
if you all choose to use it,
I think it'll make it even more valuable for you.
Super powerful. That's great. Exciting. Thank
You. So again, this,
this does exist
and if you looked into it like, hey,
I have these SOPs on Google Drive
and it's integrated, so when you make changes in Claude, um,
I've seen the changes myself.
I just don't like, um, I don't like relying like, oh,
this is gonna change 'cause I did this in Claude
and then assume that my Google drive is updated.
Um, so it's just a, a tip.
Thank you, Josh. Just one follow up question.
So, uh, it won't go, it won't reference the other chats,
but if I explicitly ask him to go
and take the context out of a chat, will he do it then?
It's a good question. I, you know what?
I don't know the answer.
Um, okay, so, um, I would, you could test it.
Um, but again, I, my, the point of what I would just for,
for everyone's purposes is like when you're in a chat, it's,
it's pulling that chat.
So you're doing a specific assessment, right?
There's like, Hey, this is what you're doing,
and then potentially where you are, you're then adding the,
the prompts for the SOP creation on that chat.
Now, when you're doing that, like when you're in delivery
to success that you're all gonna do following the session,
you then it's pulling from all the knowledge from sale
to delivery that you already did.
Does that make sense? So it's like all of your pro,
like the master prompt, it has all that context,
but I, I don't believe that it pulls from like, all
of your chats, because that would be, I mean, if you did
that, I, I'm pretty confident the answer's no, Christina,
just because if you did that, then you would just run out
of your context window instantly.
Like when you're doing
Yeah, it's just understanding the architect, you know, uh,
uh, how, what it, what it does.
I mean, as you said to just to, to, to not assume
because that is bas that's dangerous, right?
Yeah. And it works. Like if you guys look it up,
you can see that functionality, um, again,
like I've seen it happen.
I'll be like, oh, I'm gonna go change this
and check Google Drive and it, it works.
Um, but yeah, I, it's just part of me.
Um, I'm not a perfectionist by any means.
I'm a done is better than perfect guy,
but I do wanna make sure that things get done.
You know, that's, that's most important for me.
So I will say this guys, for the sake of time, um,
I am just going to, um, share kind
of the next steps we discussed.
Um, and of course, if anybody has any other questions
or you're going through the assessments that things come up,
like a lot of the, the stuff I, I sort
of told you about could happen.
Um, certainly ask questions in circle.
Um, we're, we're there to support you,
and then we will have office hours later on in the week.
And Midori, if you just want to kind of take us home
through everybody's next steps.
Yeah, I'll do this really quickly in the interest of time.
I know we're running over time today.
Uh, and Josh went through things in pretty fine detail.
So just to recap that, we have six exercises
that we're completing before Friday.
First, we're adding the five Rs to your master point
to give you a sense of, uh,
what customer excellence looks like within your, um,
business and how you can excel at them.
Then we're running the assessment, the delivery
to success assessment, uh, to sort of give a sense
of your organization's performance, um,
and identify some areas for improvement.
We're then mapping out your customer
journey and ascension points.
Uh, and from there we're gonna create level one
and level two of your SOP for the delivery to success.
Uh, from here we're creating the priority implementation MA
matrix, and that's version one, again, an iterative process
that, uh, we've repeated today.
Uh, and the last thing is that we're gonna explore ways
of organizing the SOPs.
Um, you may have a way that you're already doing this, uh,
within your company or your organization,
and it may just make sense to stick with that.
But, uh, you know, we'll share
that notion template in circle as well.
So you have a, a few things to consider.
Uh, this week we have office hours on Wednesday,
same time as the live session.
So that's 10:00 AM Pacific time, 1:00 PM Eastern Time,
sorry, that we're using, uh, north American time here.
Uh, our live session, uh, continues on Friday
where we're gonna go into marketing and brand equity.
And, uh, in the interim as well,
if you have any questions, we'll see you in circle.
All right. Thanks everyone. Appreciate you all.
Um, and let us know if you have, uh,
any questions as things come up.
Otherwise, we will either see you Wednesday on office hours,
bring your questions there.
That is a, an open q and a,
but also the format that you can share your screen we'll,
we'll go deep, uh, for whatever you you all need
as you're, you're going through this process.
And otherwise, we will see you on live session
five on Friday.
Thank you. Thank you. Good day. Thank you.
All right, talk soon. Bye.